<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Feature Engineering on Balint Bojko</title>
    <link>/tags/feature-engineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Feature Engineering on Balint Bojko</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/feature-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>BDA Competition 2 - Recognizing daily physical activity from phone sensor signals</title>
      <link>/blog/bda-competition-2-recognizing-daily-physical-activity-from-phone-sensor-signals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/bda-competition-2-recognizing-daily-physical-activity-from-phone-sensor-signals/</guid>
      <description>Description of projectThis competition involves building a classifier that recognizes different types of physical activity from signals measured by the accelerometer and gyroscope in your smartphone, which both measure aspects of movement and orientation. The data for this competition were collected in a lab using a basic smartphone in experiments with human participants carrying out various daily activities in set order.
The experiments were carried out with a group of 30 volunteers within an age bracket of 19-48 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BDA Competition 1 - Predicting Personality from vlogger videos</title>
      <link>/blog/bda-competition-1-predicting-personality-from-vlogger-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/bda-competition-1-predicting-personality-from-vlogger-videos/</guid>
      <description>Description of projectThe YouTube personality dataset consists of a collection of behavorial features, speech transcriptions, and personality impression scores for a set of 404 YouTube vloggers that explicitly show themselves in front of the a webcam talking about a variety of topics including personal issues, politics, movies, books, etc. There is no content-related restriction and the language used in the videos is natural and diverse.
Your team should employ any of the methods discussed in some detail in Chapter 3 of ISLR (James, Witten, Hastie &amp;amp; Tibshirani, 2017), in combination with creative feature engineering and feature selection, to obtain the best numerical predictions for all the personality axes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>